<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<MAIN>
	<NEWS>
		
		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20171105"
			time="1314"
		>
<title>Science Week (#8)</title>
<content>Science Week was this month and each class did some extra experiments and work in Science to mark this special week. 
We had the Electronic Brainbox workshop in the school for 3rd-6th Classes.</content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>

		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20180605"
			time="1024"
		>
<title>First Confession (#2)</title>
<content>Well done to the pupils in second class who made their First Confession this month. 
They were a credit to our school and to their families. Thank you to Fr. Ted, our teachers and parents who helped to prepare the children for the sacrament. </content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>
		
		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20180605"
			time="1427"
		>
<title>FAI 5-a-side Soccer (#1)</title>
<content>Our boys’ team did really well in reaching the semi-final of their competition recently. 
They scored 17 goals over 5 matches. Everyone commented that they were the best soccer team there. 
They lost out narrowly to the eventual winners so they can be very proud of their achievement.</content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>
		
		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20180407"
			time="1315"
		>
<title>Child Protection (#4)</title>
<content>On Tuesday this week our staff availed of in-service on the new Child Protection Guidelines. 
We engaged with an online training module from the PDST (Professional Development Service for Teachers). 
We went through our new Child Safeguarding Statement (formerly Child Protection Policy) and considered The Child Safeguarding Risk Assessment. 
The happiness, wellbeing and safety of the children in our care is something that we take very seriously and this day’s work was a vital part of this</content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>
		
		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20180418"
			time="1114"
		>
<title>Parking outside the school (#3)</title>
<content>Please do not use the staff car park in the mornings or evenings. 
Staff need to be able to access their spaces so they can come into work and take charge of your children.
They should not be obstructed from leaving in the evening either. 
The car park is also our assembly area, in case of a fire, so it needs to be kept free. 
The set down area is for parents to drop their children and leave. 
If you wish to bring your child into the school you can park a little further up the road. 
Please don’t park on the double yellow lines or in front of our neighbours’ houses/entrances.</content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>
		
		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20180401"
			time="1643"
		>
<title>Contact details (#5)</title>
<content>We use Text-a-Parent as a means of communicating reminders to you. 
We may also, on occasion need to contact you during the day if something happens to your child. 
Please make sure that we have the correct contact details for you. 
The number you provide must be a number that will be answered as it could be an urgent matter to do with your child.</content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>

		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20180320"
			time="1202"
		>
<title>Board of Management (#6)</title>
<content>Our Board of Management’s term of office is coming to an end on November 30th. 
Over the next few weeks we will be starting the process of electing a new Board to run our school.
Each Board of management is made up of 2 Patron’s nominees, 2 parents’ nominees (one mother and one father), 2 community nominees and 2 staff nominees. 
We will be looking for nominations for parent’s nominees shortly. </content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>

		<NEWS-ITEM
			yyyyMMdd="20171221"
			time="1515"
		>
<title>Holy Communion and Confirmation (#7)</title>
<content>Holy Communion is on Saturday May 21st and our Confirmation is on Friday April 15th.</content>
		</NEWS-ITEM>

		
	</NEWS>
</MAIN>